If you wouldn't mind.
Got it.
Okay, we're going to call to order the Town of Andover Board of Selectmen
Special Meeting Budget Workshop
for Monday, 03/06/2023
at
07:03PM.
We're going to start with the Pledge of Allegiance.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of The United States Of America and to the republic for which it stands,
one nation One nation. Of God,
indivisible indivisible with liberty.
Justice.
>> For all.
Excellent.
Thank you.
We're gonna move on to public speak.
Joanie Ebert.
All set. Thanks.
>> Okay.
And telephone
number, I'm not sure if that's Dennis, but telephone number at the bottom.
Yes, it's Dennis.
>> Dennis, how are you, sir? Alright.
Glad you joined us, Dennis. I'm fine. Thank you. Excellent.
Okay. So last meeting, we
we had gone through
budget
line by line with Eric,
and he had highlighted some items for us to consider and come back and vote. So Paula wanted to
be more
organized as we move forward. So
Eric,
what items are you, other than the yellow ones, do you want us to deal with today?
>> Okay. So I'm going to share a screen
real quick,
I think.
Sure.
>> Let's hope I get the right one.
Okay, so these are the items you asked me to put on this meeting's
agenda
to review. A couple of them we might not get till next meeting,
but these were the things you wanted to discuss and then also talk about the salaries.
So number one was add money under budget line item three thirty nine.
Eric, are you sharing? Are you sharing?
I thought I was. Can't see it. Okay.
>> There we go. Am I sharing now? Yes. Of course, sir. Sorry about that. No problem. So item number one, add $35,000
to the budget underlying three three nine for RAV four hybrid vehicle for senior transportation.
Jeff had done a bunch of research
on costs.
It looks like $35,000
should cover.
Jeff, do you have more info regarding that?
>> No, they're looking into it and seeing if they can comply with the
state buying program and see what they can give us for a figure. But budgetary, I think that's probably good.
It'll probably come in a little bit less than that, but we should just probably budget for it just in case there's any price increases and we don't get until this fall or this year when the new models are out.
>> Okay.
So do we just want to make a motion for that one? Do we want to make a motion for each one of these as he goes through it or do we want Eric to run through them all?
>> I think,
I don't know. I'm inclined to say one at a time unless somebody disagrees.
>> No, I have no problem with that.
Jeff, when did you say Adrian was getting on?
He's on now.
Six sixty two is his
>> can't see the phone number. Okay, so Adrian's on. So let's make a motion on the
I mean, alright, let's discuss the vehicle for senior transportation. Does anyone have a problem with that vehicle or a vehicle for senior transportation?
>> The only thing I was throwing out there is we could get a minivan for 3,000 more.
I don't know what the wish list is, but I think probably once this is approved, we could probably get the minivan for 35,000.
So we could probably get a choice of either or when the time comes.
>> Okay.
I mean, don't have to put in
the motion that we're going to buy a specific vehicle. That's what I'm saying. I just say we had $35,000
>> for a hybrid vehicle for semen transportation or just for a vehicle.
Seconded. General. Yeah.
All right. So what's the motion?
35,000.
>> Jeff Murray, the motion for this one. I'd like to make the motion to add $35,000
to the budget under line three thirty nine for a hybrid vehicle for senior transportation.
I'll second. Seconded.
>> Okay.
All right. Further discussion on that item?
Let's
vote. All those in favor? Aye. Aye. So
for nothing.
Okay.
>> Okay.
Item number two, add $30,000
to the budget under the building maintenance fund earmarked towards improvements for the Andover Museumold
Town Hall.
And again,
this is the easiest way to do that.
Put the money in the building maintenance fund,
but just state right up front that the reason why we're increasing that
is so that we can make improvements to the museum,
we can satisfy the state historic preservation office,
that we can build the senior transportation
facility.
Okay.
Is that a that a number? It's 30,000.
>> I'm just wondering, should we be specific what we're using it for? Like, door replacement, window replacement? What are we really doing there?
>> I think the priority
is number one, door replacements,
which we have to do anyway, because we have two,
actually three doors
where the sills are completely rotted out. So that's the first thing.
And then the second priority
is redoing
the ceiling
in the the low
roofed front entrance
area
of the museum. Those are the two. And then after that would be addressing,
addressing windows.
But we're not you know, the 30,000 isn't gonna stretch to addressing windows.
And I think we have some flexibility.
If we end up spending more than that, I mean, we do have because this is a building maintenance fund.
Can just take additional
money from the building maintenance fund,
you know, depending on how far out this goes. The other thing is that as long as we have money committed and we know we're agreeing to do this, it doesn't even say we have to do it this year.
So we can potentially put this project off
as long as we're earmarking some funds for in a permanent fund.
That make Is
>> correct amount this
for what they're looking for?
As was close a as I can. Specific amount, wasn't it? Well, it was not a specific amount,
>> but I think something in the $30,000
range would make them happy.
I mean, they haven't outright told me, you know, you have to spend X or we won't approve it, but I think that's in the range that we need to be contemplating for them.
>> Can
you get that number?
Like what X is, like what they require us to spend?
Like what if it's $50,000
I mean, I'm not even worried about the downside, but what if it's $50,000
>> we take an extra 20 out of the existing building maintenance fund,
and we prioritize
that next year, or we put it off the following year, and then we decrease the fund $10,000 this year and $10,000 next year.
>> My issue is I just want to make sure that we specify that's what the improvements we're going to do. Because when we get to the budget hearing,
I just want to make sure that we highlight that it's to replace the rotten doors, replace the ceiling.
We should probably specify what we're using that money for because I'm sure we're going to get asked.
Well, they can go visit.
>> Yeah, I know. Can go visit, but you know how the meetings go. Just the more information we can put up front, probably the better.
>> Well, it's, you know
well, let's make a motion on that one because we need to Okay. Build the other
So, who wants to make that one, this motion?
>> I can do it if you want. Sure. Love it. I'd like to make the motion to add $30,000
to the budget under the bill of maintenance fund earmarked towards improvements to the Andover Museum Old Town Hall to replace rotting doors and ceiling repairs.
I'll second.
>> I'll second. All right. Further discussion on this item?
No? All those in favor?
Aye. Aye.
For nothing.
All right.
>> Increase funding for direct programs by $10,000 to support
a paid staff working on programming for the department.
>> So this was in this was something you asked to put in the budget at the last meeting
to do a better job of
supporting
all of the rec programs
that the town is currently running, which are now run a 100% by volunteer effort,
or mostly.
Is that enough money?
Actually How much are you putting in? $10,000.
Yeah. I think it's enough to start.
Yeah. I would agree.
Okay.
>> I mean, remember this, we're trying to do baby steps here so that, you we we have this money in. And then once the community center is up and running, we can then expand that out if we need to. You know? Eric, do you have a line item for that one?
Yes.
Hang on.
So
(603) 870-4503,
Rec Commission.
It went past it.
Oh, can you see that screen? Oh, okay. 4153.
Yep.
A little bit higher.
Oh, actually,
>> they're not sequenced.
It's on row 40
Row
396.
Keep going. Sorry. A 100 a 100 rows down. They're not sequenced in order.
There you go.
>> Yeah, so I just put it, what I did for right now until you make that decision,
is put a placeholder in in programs.
And then if you make that decision, I'll add a line item for,
you know, essentially salary there,
that's how you want to do it.
>> Eric, you said it's, you got a note here for reviewed by Carol. She's reviewed this?
>> Well, not that part. Okay. She reviewed she reviewed all the rec commission budget,
but, obviously, she's in Hawaii. I haven't, you know, said to to Carol,
>> you know, interrupted her on her vacation. Yep. Gotcha. I just didn't know if she had gotten ahold of you and reviewed it or not. Nope. So maybe
we'll get rid of that. Okay.
Alright. So
>> Just
a note of reference. We probably shouldn't be
saying when people are somewhere or somewhere else, like, you know, Carol's not putting it out there on social media. I don't think so.
Let's not do that here, Roger. That's
a good point. My apologies.
Thank you.
>> Eric, put your other
screen up.
There it is. Back to me. Sorry. I got too many things open. No. You're good. You're good right here.
So I'll make a motion
to increase funding
for
the
rec commission budget 4,503
line
I don't even know how you look at the lines on these, Eric. Do you use 55990
or 60300And87?
What do you use?
Hang on.
>> How do you want to reference it?
Programs.
Okay.
So I can get on with it. All right. Go back to the other screen.
So I'll make a motion to increase funding for
the Recreation
Commission budget line or Budget
4503,
line 607055990,
dollars 10,000
to support
paid staff
for programming
to benefit the
total community, seniors and children.
I'll second.
>> Further discussion on that item, anybody?
No. All those in favor? Aye. Aye.
Okay.
>> Item number four, keep or eliminate the temp help position for public works, which is 3,000 and one-one
-fifty
1,000
public works
temp salary.
So, again, this was the ask by Scott
to essentially fund a part time position
to deal with field
stuff.
Which I
totally get his frustration with the level of input he's had to have
into the field for field maintenance.
You know? And the question is, do we try to use, do we try to hire somebody to do that, or do we just flat out
assign that to
Jay and say, have public works make this happen,
which is the other possibility?
>> Can we push this one off until Scott's back for our next meeting?
Yep. Certainly can.
>> Anybody have a problem with that? Is
Jay on tonight?
>> Jay is not on tonight.
When is Jay's schedule? Next week? Jay will be back next week. Yeah. Unfortunately
or fortunately,
wife bought him surprise tickets to the
UConn Women's Basketball,
you know finals.
And told them this afternoon.
So he was a little bit mortified that.
>> He's good good to go so let's just push that we're going to push down on them off then Yeah. If we can get a list of what Scott's looking for, I just wondered if we can just contract this or if we can just do it through employees. Yeah. That's that's my question as well. You know, if we can have a landscaping company or somebody manage, you know, manage it, then
I'd rather do that if possible.
Think he
>> said last meeting he was talking to Christine
Randazzo,
who has a landscaping company. I think she hadn't gotten back to him. So I don't know if that's what he was talking to her about.
>> He might have Really the bulk of what yeah, I thought the bulk of what he's looking for is help with the sprinkler system.
>> If
I understood him correctly and from conversations, he's just looking for someone to check it out in the mornings
and make sure there's no problems because that's always what he was doing. He was going over there to check
on it, see if it was running properly, and if it was not, he was troubleshooting.
>> That's what he's after. So that's why he believes public works would be the best for it, you know, when Let's let's wait for Scott and try to sort that. Yeah. And if that if that's your statement that if they're looking for the sprinkler system, public works might be the best option then because they do do their drive around in the morning,
and they can just make that a stop.
>> Yeah.
So let's have Scott go through what he has to do to what he does personally to deal
with that.
Okay.
Next one.
>> Okay.
Item number five. I sent you all today
the Jay's revised
cost
spreadsheet,
which
was the Capital Roads
spreadsheet.
And then I also sent you a two page Word doc
that was basically the outlines
of the pavement management plan that we have kind of in place.
The real bottom line is there's kind of two takeaways. The first is last year we overspent,
but the reality is we had to do
the reclamation last year because if not, we were going to lose our grant funding.
And,
you know, that was the cost basis for doing that was much higher last year than we anticipated.
In
fact, the cost of doing it last year with the grant
would have been the same as the cost doing it,
you know, the year before
without the grant, which is kind of scary.
Similarly,
when we really look at seal, the cost of chip seal per square yard is up about 60%
over what it was three years ago, four years ago.
So, we are looking at some pretty significant
cost increases with that.
However,
we're doing reasonably well overall
in town.
So, if you wanted to say let's
level fund
on today's basis, what it would cost
to stay on the seven year track
for touching all of our roads,
that would equate to increasing the road improvement front from about 330,000
to about 375,000
to keep pace with increased costs.
So those are where the numbers kind of work out.
The other real issue that public works faces is that
they count on leaving a fair amount of money to be spent,
you know, between
say
March
and July 1 when the new budget year starts.
Because to get all the roadwork done, you really need to do a bunch of it before July 1.
And because we
overspent fairly considerably last year,
we took that reserve cushion that we had been maintaining
and we spent
the heck out of it. So we're going to,
you know, we're going to have to deal with that over the next couple years. We're just not going to have that
nice cushion that we had in years previous.
That's kind of the summary
of that.
That's just the spring though, right?
What do you mean?
>> The fee you're saying we're not gonna have that because of the
because we overspent last year. So going into this spring, we don't have the funds that we normally would have. Right?
>> Correct.
Correct.
Right now, could
say we have about $100,000
we can spend before July 1
in that ballpark.
Most years,
at this time, we have somewhere in the range of $300,000
we tend to all the shim
prior to, and the total cost for the shim run a couple $100,000.
And at the same time,
we're doing the catch basin cleaning, and we may be doing the guardrails and some of the other stuff too.
So, Don't we count on another we
tar payment coming in?
We already got the TAR payment.
>> You did get it? Okay. Yep. So that's base so, basically, you're saying we have the TAR payment we can use?
>> Right.
Yes.
When Right. I
But that's it.
I mean, our road improvement fund has zero in it.
>> Can
Can we we use start those funds, though, instead of spreading them thin on chip or something else? Can we use them to start
prep for drainage on on a road that we need to do anyways?
So the guys have something
they can dig into that's gonna take time, but not necessarily a lot of money and get ready for a fall project that we can then do?
Alexa, how So are we addressing
>> yes.
The first thing is we're
probably going to have to put off
some of the early shim work that we would like to do
because you're right, we are gonna need to divert some money into replacing because last year we also depleted a lot of our stock
in catch basins and basin tops and pipe and stuff like that. So
what we're going to do is we're going to do the minimum,
at the minimum we need to function right now between July 1,
you know, but get public works
in as early as possible,
starting on Hendi with the drainage. With the plan being doing Hendi,
that section of Long Hill Road between
Hendy and Skinner. What?
Oh, sorry. And then
Skinner to Wheeling and beyond if we can get to it. And the major drainage effort
this year be doing that stretch.
>> And this may be a Jay question, but is there a reason we haven't put
funds in this budget, even if it's 30,000 or 40,000
to replace some of those supplies so that we have some supplies on hand?
In which budget?
>> I mean, next coming up. Yeah. Next year's budget. Do we have are we putting funds on the table
to be able to have, replace some of those basin caps and things like that that we need to have on hand to some extent?
>> Yes. In fact, if you look in,
let me bring up the
transfer over the capital budget.
If you look at drainage,
there's
a fairly good, this is basically
cost for materials
for drainage
to restock.
Because up until this year, we've maintained a fairly significant stock.
We drained it down last year. Now we're going to refill it and keep using it.
Okay. So yes, there is a fair bit of money in there for replacement
of supplies.
Okay.
Thank you. Yep.
Did I answer that question?
Yep.
I'm good.
>> So, Eric, if if you're you're basically saying it takes us approximately
at
current cost $17,000,000
to redo all of the Andover Roads.
>> If you wanted to
so eventually everything has to get reclaimed.
You know, you can go a long time before you reclaim it, but eventually everything would get reclaimed
and reclaiming everything once is about 17,000,000.
But
we're not gonna do a whole lot of reclaiming just because the cost basis for that is prohibitive.
So what I'm doing is every time I get a chance that there's a grant where I can apply for funding or partial funding to do some reclaiming
and repaving,
we will.
And we're gonna prioritize kind of the backbone roads, which is why we did the first section of Long Hill, the first section of Shoddy, and now we're looking at the section of Hendy, the Long Hill, the Skinner,
to see whether we can reclaim significant sections of the backbone.
That's
kind of the goal there.
>> Okay, so we're going to take this information that you did, and we're going to meet with Jay next week.
That accurate?
>> Yep, that's totally accurate. I mean, I'll answer other questions if
you have them, but
I think you probably ought to wait for his input.
But I can give you the big picture numbers that given the cost increases
in materials costs
and the cost to do work,
you're definitely looking at increasing the road improvement fund if you want to maintain
something level with what we've been doing the last few years.
Okay.
>> Anybody have any questions on the document that Eric provided us or any questions,
thoughts related to what
we need to look at?
>> It sounds like basically we to
wait until we talk to Jay before we make any moves.
Is that correct?
Yeah, I mean
>> Yeah, four and five should be weighted. We should wait on four and five. Do we have the people present?
>> Okay.
That's fine. We'll do that next week. So item six.
>> So
I also sent you as a group
a basically
an outline of how it would work.
So, as most of you know, we do have
RFP
out for a planning firm to do the plan of conservation and development.
The
committee picked
who they wanted as a vendor.
And then, you know, we also started exploring what would happen if instead of doing just the POCD,
We hired this person for two years
with the primary goal of hiring them be the POCD,
but also to provide some of the other planning services
and how that would look like budgetarily.
So this is basically how it would work. We would need to add
about 36,000
to this year's budget.
We would then reduce the legal and professional line item, which covered some of that
by $5,000
We would no longer fund the POCD
implementation
fund
because we would be getting our POCD
with our own planner, not by hiring outside firm.
So that would save us $5,000
And then we would take money from the existing
POCD implementation
fund
and offset the cost of the planner for the next two years.
Now we still have to do a little research in this because there's only $24,000
in the POCD implementation fund,
and there should be like around 40.
And I don't understand where the difference is, but that's going to take some digging because I thought starting right at the end of the last POCD cycle,
the Board of Finance
funded it every year,
which should put us at about 40,000
now.
So we got to do some historical research and find out why there's only 24,000
in that fund currently.
But that's basically how the math will would work.
We
do have a Warner is on for the next meeting to
be there to answer any questions you may have
about what a planner
could do for the town.
He's not the planner we would be hiring,
but I think it's good to have somebody that can talk to you that, you know,
essentially is not seeking the job here, but we'll talk to you about what a planner can do for a small town.
>> So if your numbers are correct, you're talking about a $13,000
increase
in the overall budget for the planner in this fiscal year or the budgeted fiscal year that we're talking?
It would be a $26,000
increase.
>> Because Isn't the Board of Finance gonna use $13,000
from the implementation fund?
>> No. That's going to be in addition to the 36,000.
So what they what what
they wanted for just the POCD
was around 72,000.
What
and I asked a couple of the other towns that they work for.
What he what their planning firm does is when they assign somebody to the town,
you know, you basically
we're gonna take him in a one one day a week increment.
So and they charge $48,000
a year for that. So it's a big chunk of change.
But if you think about it, our cost just to do the POCD would be around 72,
which is way more than we had.
You know, now we're spending 96,
but we're also getting,
you know, additional planning services above and beyond
the
POCD.
So that would be how it would work.
And again, I suggest you wait and talk to the planner before you make any kind of decisions,
But that's kind of what I laid out to you in
my
letter to you.
>> So
can you just clarify? So
once the initial
first year is done
and we're
moving forward, let's say that the the the POCD is done, but now we're we're using them for
a town planner. What is the town planner cost per year at that point?
>> If we kept them at that same time,
it would be 48,000
a year.
However,
I don't think we need to retain them at that same amount of time.
And we have discussed reducing,
you know, what it would look like to reduce their hours.
So I think we could
end up with a number that's definitely less than that,
but it's not, you know, it's still gonna be a bigger number than we'd really like.
>> Okay. So next week
is next is next week Bill Warner also on? Yes.
So we have Bill Warner and Jay.
Correct.
>> Right. And so four, five and six are all going to be carried over for next week.
Anybody got a problem with that?
Nope.
No.
>> All right. Do we have anything else that we want to do related to the budget?
Individual line items? Anybody want to sit there and discuss anything related to it?
Okay. So if anyone wants to add anything to the
list of items for next week,
just communicate with Eric and get them on the list.
>> Jeff, do we still have to deal with the salaries?
Yes. I was just gonna ask that.
>> Is is that something we wanna put in just as a budgetary item and have the board of finance iron that out because it's eventually their decision? Or
>> So two things.
Technically,
salary is your decision,
not the Board of Finances,
but it is only your decision for those employees
that are
not elected
and not union because
obviously there's contracts to them already.
Although those are kind of your union contracts are your decisions also because ultimately you're the ones that have to ratify union contracts.
>> All right. So we
have the town administrator,
the
the public works supervisor, and the library director that we need to discuss.
Is that accurate?
>> For
some reason, I'm trying to pull up the other form, and I'm struggling here at the moment.
>> It's it's in the little box that you're seeing on your screen. Do it again. Well,
the watching your ways go away.
God, it freaking
makes me crazy.
>> Which one are you trying to get to? You've been to that one five times.
Are you trying to get to that one? Okay, now click on it. You
got to get to this. There's a little box up top. It's shrunk. There you go.
>> There we go. There we go. So this is the one I wanted to show you. This is basically
all of the employees
that are under your purview.
Last week, you asked me back to put back in the salary for the first selectman,
but to set it the same as the other selectman.
So that's that.
And then this is all the other employees
and
what a
range of raise possibilities
would look like.
The ones that are in green
are
library clerks
that need to come up to a dollar an hour to make minimum wage.
So that's why those are in red. Those are the minimum increases
you can give them.
So that's what that looks like, what it looks like at a 2%, 3%, and 4%.
Can you send us that spreadsheet?
Are
>> the library numbers correct? Because it looks like all the same lines are the same number.
The 2%, 3%, 4%.
>> Yeah, because no matter what percent,
you can't give them a two or three or 4%
>> raise because that's So they have the the fifty minute raise. Got you. You're not allowed to do that. So that's the minimum, right. Yeah.
>> It's just a question as a group.
Thing is, Eric, does this spreadsheet tell us what if we said 3%
raise or 4% raise or 7% raise, what the total increase is?
Just for the items that we're trying to deal with?
>> So
this
says
if you do a 2% increase, the total cost of the town across those employees
is about $10,000
And
there's your range.
And that's everybody
in this wall.
>> That's everybody that's
part of that in that group.
And the only one I would suggest out of that is I do think you should do better than,
you know, you should go for a 5% raise for Jay because I think in this case he is worth that,
that raise.
But that's just what I think. You may think something different.
>> Does anyone want to sit there and
Well,
let's let's so we get it out in the open. What are the union raises this year?
>> 2.9%
for MEIU.
We don't have a contract
for either the current year or the next year with AFSCME yet, so no idea what that will be. But we're certainly assuming
it's gonna be the same as
MEIU.
So if we said So if you wanted, you could simply match and say 2.9%
and recalculate based on that if that was your preference or
whatever you so choose.
>> So if we said 3%,
our total cost
increase is $14,000
a little less than that, but $13,800
Correct.
>> We scroll up a little bit and see the other positions too, just as we're all talking about everything.
Okay. That looks better.
Maybe I can go down one.
>> Would
would make a motion that we
do a 2.9
raise to match
what the
the union's getting for those employees.
And I would do a 4% raise for Jay.
That'd be my motion.
>> What are you basing
that on, Adrian? What's your thought? Why do you want to do
J at 4% instead of point nine?
>> Because Eric said Well, I mean, I think J is
definitely due.
We didn't do a
we didn't do a contract renegotiation or anything with him. So he's been off contract for a while. And that challenging you He got just to what everybody else got last year. Yeah. I just wanted to see what
you were thinking. Well, I think he got what everybody else got last year, but I think
also, you know, when he first came in, we were very cautious about,
I guess, what we were paying him. And
if you look around at the impact he's had, I personally think
that he's definitely shown some level of impact that justifies.
I just don't know. I don't know that the townsfolk are gonna be okay with 5%.
And I think
given the level of impact he's had, he certainly deserves more than the the the standard.
But I don't know that
I don't know that the townspeople in general are gonna say it's okay to get him a lot more.
So I guess I'm splitting the difference.
>> You
know?
He does not have a contract right now, Lewis?
Currently,
no.
Nope. He's off contract.
>> Should we be considering getting Jay on contract?
I would consider that.
>> Yes.
We should be considering getting Jay on contract.
Renewing his contract. But but
>> let's let's have an honest conversation about what what difference does a contract make.
You know? A a noncompete is almost unenforceable.
Right?
If you put them on a contract, you're telling them ahead of time how much he's gonna make
with increases.
So,
you know
>> Well, is Jay coming We'll from
have to ask him next week.
>> Well, Jay hasn't come to us since his contract expired, that's been a while. So
you know?
I
mean, Jay's a manager. Right? It's not up to us to go to him and ask him if he's okay with it. He should be in a position as a as a manager to be able to come to us and say, hey. You know, I want a contract.
He hasn't done that. So
why would we go to him?
That's my own take on it.
Uh-huh.
It's a nice I'm
sorry. I didn't I didn't catch that.
It's a nice gesture,
Adrian.
>> That's how I look at it. We're not talking about being nice. We're talking about management here. This is not being nice. It's about money. I
see. I see your point.
Your point.
You know,
is about business.
>> Well,
maybe this is a conversation we need to have with Jay when he can give us his feedback.
I understand, Adrian, that, you
know, I'm I'm I'm thinking
like you you are. That's why I asked about the union because do we want to sit there and get so far out in front of the contract
and give our union members
I'll second your motion, Adrian.
Any further discussion on the motion?
I'll
discuss it myself. Mean,
it's reasonable,
but it's unreasonable.
It's not a
mean.
So
I mean, The value of some of the perks
>> the value of some of the perks that we're already giving Jay,
you know, he has a he has a town vehicle that he's allowed to take to and from.
You know, he doesn't pay for gas in that vehicle,
that's a that's a pretty concise benefit in and of itself given the cost of fuel right now.
You know? So he's already
reaping the benefits of some of that. That's why I don't think 5% is justified.
>> Okay. I'm
assuming all these library
clerks, though, that
do we want a revised motion to
deal with them?
>> Because the
other percentage doesn't get them there. So we have to address them at least to bring them up to minimum wage.
So
if you want to revise it, I'll second
that
revision that we bring the
library employees up to minimum wage.
>> Or just state that
all employees,
the minimum salary for all employees will be minimum wage.
That covers it.
>> And any employee that's not on minimum wage would go to 2.9%
with the exception of Jay Tuttle, which would go to 4%.
Except the children's librarian, which is $16.25.
Right.
Why
is that one different?
>> Because
so she gets paid two different ways.
She
acts as the children's librarian,
and she acts as just a regular clerk,
depending on what she's doing on a particular day. So she gets more money if she's working as a children's librarian.
>> And to be clear, it's not because I care that someone's making $16.25
an hour or whatever. I was curiosity.
Correct.
>> Okay.
Let's bring
the motion as revised to
a vote.
All those in favor,
aye.
Aye.
>> Okay.
None opposed.
So we'll pass that to the Board of Finance.
Okay. Anything else that we need to discuss tonight before we move on?
Okay.
So all we have left
before we move to
the executive session,
Let's
Oh my god. My
agenda went away.
There it is.
We did not
put public speak on the agenda.
But we'll go to public speak before we go to executive session. So Joann Ebert,
would you like to
add anything?
>> Thank you. Just here to listen to your discussion.
Thanks.
>> Okay.
All right.
Somebody want to make a motion to move to executive session?
I make a motion to move to executive session.
Invite the town attorney.
>> Invite the town attorney. Are we inviting Eric too?
Yes. Yes. And Eric,
the town administrator.
Okay.
Adrian seconded.
All those in favor, aye.
Aye.
Aye. Eric, if you can stop the recording.